# Abhinav Kumar Singh (1) Featured

Developer seeking roles in SnapLogic, jda/blueyonder WM, Python, GCP, Bigguery and mulesoft



Current Designation: Application Developer Total Experience: 4 Year(s) 7 Month(s)

Highest Degree: CS [CS] Current Company: Tyson Foods Inc. - Oaklawn IT Solution

Private Ltd

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Delhi / NCR, Mumbai Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Application/Software Developer, Software Engineering, Software Development, Application Development, Project

Management, Change Management, Requirement

Gathering, Programming, jQuery, Python, Oracle, HTML, SVN, Git, C, C+, snaplogic, GCP, BigQuery, JDA, BlueYonder WMS

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 22-Jan-21 Last Modified: 22-Jan-21

## **Summary**

A passionate Developer - Applications with 4.7+ years of experience, responsible for development of customer-driven features adhering to high code standards and agile methodologies. Have a strong grasp on Snaplogic integration platform and BlueYonder/Jda WM. An enthusiastic, self-motivated, reliable, energetic and a mature team player adaptable to challenging situations. Looking for further Career growth opportunities amplifying my skill set

## Work Experience

#### Tyson Foods Inc. - Oaklawn IT Solution Private Ltd as Application Developer Dec 2019 to Till Date

Project WIN Template 2 integrations covering around ten new plants that are expected to go-live in upcoming months. Snaplogic, BY/Jda WM 2019.x, Python]

have been transitioned to a Lead role for this project to work in close collaboration with mainframe, middleware and BY business teams while also managing a five member Infosys team ?Develop around 40+ ultra pipelines in Snaplogic for integrations between mainframe and BY WM ?Design and implement message flow architecture from mainframe to BY and vice-versa for integrations related to 'inventory status change', 'shipment status change', 'inventory adjustment', 'customer download' and more ?Create and configure the corresponding BY integrator interfaces and communication methods ?Configure Active MQ queues and topics to facilitate these integrations ?Design/Implement Splunk logging and email framework to track the status of any processed messages at each processing stage ?Leveraged Python via script snap for complex data transformation logic, increasing the development speed and efficiency while also keeping the design sleek and simple

Carrier download Integration between EAP, SAP BODS jobs and BY using Snaplogic

Contributed to design and implement the data flow from EAP to SAP BODS platform and then pushing that data to IBM MQ from where Snaplogic reads the json data, converts to BY xml format and passes onto the corresponding active MQ queues after transformations/validations to be consumed by the configured BY integrator interfaces

INIT pipeline executes on huge data at once during any go-live to download all required carriers to a BY plant While DELTA pipeline executes post go-live to download any new carrier or modified carrier

BY WM user download integration using Snaplogic

ARS is a platform from where users request access to BY WM plants for various roles

Process of adding/removing/modifying WM users used to be manual but we automated this process recently

Snaplogic triggered task was used as a REST api by ARS module to initiate any such requests which would in turn

transform/validate/log the data and then pass onto the corresponding BY integrator interface

Triggered pipeline was created to systematically query MySql DB hosted on AWS for new records and integrate them with SAP BAPI module

Created a Cronacle job written in Python to call the triggered task on a schedule basis

Cronacle job was preferred by architects over scheduled task for better scheduling and monitoring capabilities and Workday integration for payslips

Snaplogic, jwt, aws api]

Collaborated with aws team who had developed an api for jwt authentication which was the first contact for Workday Snaplogic pipeline would call the corresponding SAP interface for authenticated executions and pass the relevant data back to Workday via aws api

The payslip information is passed as pdf and is not saved anywhere for privacy reasons as a team to develop a proof of concept to monitor ultra pipelines in a

Besides having the standard capability of monitoring ultra pipelines offered by Snaplogic, we developed a custom framework to start or stop an ultra task automatically and also send customized emails

This included development on Snaplogic and Cronacle jobs written in Python

Enablon Farm automation and integration

Snaplogic, SOAP web-services] ?Fixed a few mapping bugs where a particular field needed to have values depending on which farm that data was meant for ?Data passed to Enablon platform via SOAP call

Go-Live projects for warehouses based out of Arizona and Indianapolis

Jda WM 2017.2] ?Supported these two go-lives ?Have been a part of the rollout teams ?Configured Jda WM according to user requirements ?Tackled multiple issues related to integration, directed work, inbound, outbound, user authentication

Development project for pending putaway inventory ?Did functional analysis for the requirement where we needed to report all inventory that has pending putaway work - directed or undirected

#### JDA Software Private Ltd. as Technical Consultant - DSS / PD Mar 2016 to Nov 2019

?JDA ABPP, JDA TM project for one of the largest producers of stainless steel in Europe ?A new feature was added on the standard TM Loads and Carriers screens ?This executes the corresponding workflows created depending on selected record's entitytype ?The two workflows and all BLs were developed in ABPP while the triggering mechanism had to be configured within TM. ?Supported issues during this feature's go-live ?JDA ABPP, JDA TM and Transwide integrations for an American multinational medical devices, pharmaceutical and consumer packaged goods manufacturing company ?The modification was completed within 2 months, ready for deployment by the customer. ?I worked on developing four BLs and three UI workflows. ?Feature involved absorbing communication from the third party application - Transwide, used by customer, into JDA TM taking care of necessary validations. Appropriate notifications would be sent to customer via various customizable channels in case of any functional/technical problems encountered, in real-time. ?JDA TM operations done by the customer were also communicated back to Transwide for further processing. ?Worked as a 2 member team of developers in collaboration with a separate cloud team. ?JDA WM, BI Reporting, WLM, MobileLink and DLS integrations for a California-based seller of fresh berries ?Major customer with multiple modification requests across many SCM segments. ?These modifications spanned over 6 months - more new requests lined up immediately. ?Involved development of multiple features, automated jobs/tasks and web UI screens. ?Reporting integrations involved creating operational reports per schedule set by customer and also on-demand. Reports included summarized data of multiple day to day operations from receiving, allocation to shipping - fully customizable by client. ?DLS integrations involved autoallocation of orders downloaded from host, updating WM system as required and tracking status of these orders throughout . ?WLM / MobileLink integrations involved responding to events logged in by MobileLink, gathering further information from WM based on provided input and sending notification to the customer. My responsibility was to create a new end to end outbound integrator transaction or this. ?In later months worked on further CRs related to above modifications. ?I was a part of 5 member team of developers, based in Bangalore . Collaborated with other teams across the globe sharing workload around shifts for guicker delivery.

JDA TM - Developed an Integrated communication channel to showcase during JDA Crystal Ball 2019 ?The idea was to incorporate a way within JDA TM, which enables customer to get real time updates from third party agencies, drivers and information about tender billing etc. Their clients will also be able to bid for services in real time. ?Developed a prototype within one month. ?I was completely responsible for UI and communication framework. ?Leveraged PubNub ChatEngine laaS for quick and effective development of a fully functional prototype. ?Worked as a 3 member team of developers. [Technical Analyst, Sep 2016 to early 2017] ?Worked on a modification for one of the world's largest distributors of electronic components and embedded solutions based out of Arizona ?My responsibility was to tune all database transactions for best performance. ?Was able to bring down execution time for a transaction from around 45 seconds to around 3 seconds, which greatly improved performance of automated jobs running in the background. This also improved loading times of UI screens which executed the same transaction during pre-load phase. ?Worked on a UI modification for the same customer ?My responsibility was to address a problem where incorrect data got affected instead of the one being chosen by the customer on UI. ?I was appreciated for resolving this and controlling customer escalations. ? Undertook multiple Jiras for an American multi-national consumer goods corporation

### **Education**

PG: CS (CS) from Centre for Development of Advanced Computing (CDAC) in 2015

### IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
BigQuery, Splunk, Jira, Active MQ,			
Oracle PL/SQL, Java, C++, C			
Svn, Git, Linux/Unix, Windows, SAP, .NET			
Python, GCP			0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
HTML, Ajax, Jquery, Javascript,			

# Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				

### **Affirmative Action**

Physically Challenged: No

### **Work Authorization**

Job Type: Permanent / Temporary

Employment Status: Full Time, Part Time